Sincro: wyxchari
你确定从来没见过他们？他们说认识你
You're quite sure you've never met these men?
They say they know you.
但他们不可能认识我，这是我第一次来英国！
But they can't know me.
This is my first visit to England!
Polly，是我们啊，是我和博士！
But Polly, it's us, me and the Doctor!
可否告诉我们你的名字？
Would you mind telling us your name?
我叫 Michelle Leuppi，来自苏黎世
I am Michelle Leuppi from Zurich.
你有护照吗？
You have a passport?
有，当然有，这里
Yes, of course. Here.
我做错什么了吗？
Have I done something wrong?
哦没有，我觉得这里没有什么你需要担心的，小姐
Oh no, I don't suppose there's anything
for you to worry about, Miss.
我可以问问你来英国做什么？
May I just ask what you're doing in England?
我是来工作的。看，这是我的工作许可
I have come here to work.
Look, here is my work permit.
哦，是，完全没问题。谢谢你，打扰了
Oh, yes, that's quite in order.
Thank you. Excuse me.
你在那里学的这么好的英语？
Where did you learn such excellent English?
我有一个英语家庭教师
I had an English governess.
你介意告诉这是怎么一回事吗？
Would you mind telling me what's happening?
没什么需要你操心的，小姐，一切都没问题
Nothing that need concern you, miss,
everything's perfectly in order.
现在你可以从这边走了
Now if you'd just like to go through there?
谢谢你
Thank you.
Polly，等等！
Polly, wait!
你先等等，年轻人
Just a minute young man.
但她是我们的朋友啊——她还看见了那场谋杀！
But she's a friend of ours - and she saw the murder!
你们俩得待在这里，直到警司到了这里——现在明白了吗？
You're going to wait here until the Superintendent
of police arrives - now understand that?
啊，你要告诉他那具死尸的事情，非常明智
Ah, you're going to tell him
about the dead body, very sensible.
不，我要告诉他你们的事情
No. I am going to tell him about you.
给我接 Reynolds 警司
Put me through to Superintendent Reynolds.
Jamie，我觉得我们在这里不是太受欢迎
Jamie, I don't think we're very welcome here.
等我说跑的时候，就跑
When I say run, we run!
你好，警司，我是总指挥
Hello Super, Commandant.
我这里有两个非法入境者
I've got a couple of illegal entrants here.
对...出入境五号柜台
Yes... Immigration Desk Number Five.
跑！
Run!
总指挥！
Commandant!
情况有变，他们刚刚逃跑了
Situation changed. They've just made a run for it.
我把他们详细描述给你...
I'll give you their description...
快！他要窒息了
Quick! He's suffocating.
你们晚了20分钟
You were twenty minutes late.
他是谁？
Who is he?
Meadows，是航空控制台的
Meadows - Air Traffic Control.
很好！他对我们有用
Good! He may be useful to us.
他们还在搜寻我们，博士
They're still hunting for us, Doctor.
是的，我们必须躲开他们，除非我们能证明我们的故事
Yes. We'll have to keep out of their way
until we can prove our story.
本来有一个很好的机会证明的//
A fine chance we have of doing that -
但Polly居然开玩笑说她不认识我们！
with Polly kidding on she doesn't know us!
我不知道 Polly 是不是在开玩笑//
I don't think Polly was kidding on.
事实上，我觉得那不是 Polly
In fact, I don't think that was Polly.
当然是，就是 Polly！你都看见了！
Of course, it was Polly! You saw her!
你不应该相信所有你说看见的事情，Jamie
You don't want to believe everything you see, Jamie.
博士
Doctor!
没人，博士
All clear, Doctor.
博士！
Doctor!
是这个，变色龙观光游
Yes, Chameleon Tours.
这是变色龙青年观光游的广告
An advertisement for Chameleon Youth Tours.
年轻人的廉价旅游，为18-25岁量身定做
"Budget Tours for young people
between the ages of eighteen and twenty five. "
- 廉价是什么意思？
- What do they mean by budget?
费用少，便宜！ 这可能是诱饵
Inexpensive, cheap! This could be the bait.
你知道变色龙是什么吗，Jamie?
Do you know what a chameleon is, Jamie?
只是个名字吧，我估计？
It's just a name, I suppose?
是一种小动物的名字，一种蜥蜴
It is the name of a small animal, a lizard
它能改变它身体的颜色，以与周边环境融为一体
that can change it's colour
to merge with it's background.
但这个名字一样可用在人身上
But it's a name that could equally
be applied to people as well.
有些人为了自己的目的会改变自己的特性
People who change their personalities
to suit their own ends.
廉价旅游...为18-25岁年轻人
Budget Tours... young people
between the ages of eighteen and twenty-five
Oh yes, there's something strange going on here.
- 博士！Jamie！  - Ben！你没事吧
- Doctor! Jamie!  - Ben! Are you all right?
- 嗯，我没事 - 那还真松了一口气
- Yeah, I'm okay.  - Well that's a relief.
你们俩怎么了？Polly 又在哪儿？
What happened to you two and where's Polly?
我们不能在这里聊，得找个地方躲起来
We can't talk here.
We've got to find somewhere to hide.
躲那些找我们要护照的
Something about passports.
我正好有个地方，快来
I've got the very place. Come on.
他没事吧
Is he all right?
看看吧
We'll see.
读第一行
Read the first line!
发声控制器
Vocal control.
试试那个
Try that.
H... X... O... A...
都搞定了
All complete.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我的名字是George Meadows
My name is George Meadows.
我在航空控制塔台工作，盖特威克机场
I work at Air Traffic Control, Gatwick Airport.
你住在哪里？
Where do you live?
希尔维亚大街10号
Number Ten, Sylvia Avenue.
10号？
Number Ten?
在上周之前，我们住在34号
Until last week, We lived at Number Thirty-Four.
我前一段太忙，还没有将这个变化通知人事部门
I've been too busy to tell
the Personnel Department of the change.
太棒了！
Excellent!
- 快看！那是Polly!  - 是的
- Look! There's Polly!  - Yes.
你看她在给谁干活！
Look who she's working for!
- 变色龙观光旅游  - 是的
- Chameleon Tours.  - Yes.
把这交给我吧
Leave this to me.
Polly​
Polly.
请走开
Please go away.
看，你肯定出事了，Polly
Now, something has happened to you, Polly.
我期望你尽力想起我们离开机库之前的事情
I want you to try to remember
up to the time we left the hangar.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
想想，Polly。当时我们三个在机库
Now think, Polly.
There were three of us in the hangar.
你让我们看了点东西，是什么？
You were showing us something. Now what was it?
我跟你说，我不知道你在说些什么
I tell you, I don't know what you're talking about.
机库，Polly，变色龙的机库
The hangar, Polly, The Chameleon Hangar.
你说你还看见了是谁干的
You said you'd seen the man who did it.
我什么也没看见，我猜你是疯了
I didn't see anything. I think you're mad.
如果我看见谁被枪杀了，我会去找警察的...
If I'd seen anyone shot,
I'd have gone to the police...
谁被枪杀了？
Anyone shot?
我...我是说被谋害了
I... I mean murdered...
我可没说有人被枪杀或者被谋害了，Polly
I didn't say anyone was shot, or murdered, Polly.
求你了，能不能别烦我
Look, please, will you just leave me alone.
她这是怎么了，博士？
What's happened to her, Doctor?
我不知道，但我打算查明白
I don't know. But I mean to find out.
快来，我们找一个可以说话的地方
Come on, let's find that place where we can talk.
到这里面来
Come in here.
我本来正要跟你交待这个任务的
I was going to brief you for this assignment,
但现在没什么必要了
but there isn't any purpose, now.
是我搞砸了吗？
I have failed, then?
环境对你不利
Circumstances are against you.
我会安排你搭下一航班离开
I'll make arrangements for you
to leave on the next flight.
回基地？
Back to base?
是的
Yes.
这个人怎么办？他很执着
What about that man? He's very persistent.
不用担心他
Don't worry about him.
我们有好多方法对付这样的人
We have ways of dealing with such people...
你确定你没有见过他，先生？
Are you sure you haven't seen him, sir?
我相当确定
I'm quite sure!
哦，Jean, 这位是 Crossland 督察//
Oh Jean, this is Detective Inspector Crossland.
尽你所能给他一些协助
Give him any help you can.
- 那我先告辞了？  - 好的，当然，先生
- If you'll excuse me? - Yes, of course, sir.
好了，督察，有什么可以帮你的？
Well now Inspector, what can I do for you?
哦，我想首先我需要一张通行证
Well, I think I'll need a pass for a start.
哦，这很容易安排
Well that's easily arranged.
还有什么吗？
Anything else?
有，本来我是要跟我的一个同事碰面的
Yes, I was supposed to meet a colleague of mine here,
- 一位叫 Gascoigne 的督察  - 怎么了？
- a Detective Inspector Gascoigne.   - Yes?
他在调查一个人口失踪案//
Well, he was investigating a missing person
是从你们这里一趟租赁航班失踪的
off one of your charter flights.
但奇怪的是，他没出现
The funny thing is, he hasn't shown up!
Crossland 督察
Detective-Inspector Crossland...
我能问问你这次的公务是。。。？
What shall I say your business is?
调查变色龙青年旅游
Investigation into Chameleon Youth Tours.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这是一台给你们拍照片的机器
It's a machine that takes your photograph.
照片？
Photograph?
喏，你看你得...
Well, you see you've got...
别 Ben，现在别//
No Ben, not now.
我想不通的是，这女孩试图假扮成 Polly，但是...
What puzzles me is this girl
pretending to be Polly, yet...
某种程度上来说，她又是 Polly
yet in a way, she is Polly.
你觉得她会是被洗脑了吗？
Do you think she's been brainwashed?
不，时间不够
No, not in the time.
不管她遭遇了什么，都在短短几分钟之内。小心！
Whatever happened to her happened to her
in a few minutes. Look out!
没事了。Ben，Jamie
All right. Now Ben, Jamie,
我们必须得去多找一些变色龙观光游的情况
we've got to find out
more about Chameleon Youth Tours,
不过问题是，我们没法自由行动
but the trouble is, we're not free to move around//
当局还在找我们
with the authorities looking for us.
诶，他们并没有在找我
Well, they're not looking for me.
嗯，那倒是，你可以去机库调查
Well, that's true. You could investigate the hangar.
就交给我吧。那你们呢？
Leave it to me. Now what about you?
我要回去找总指挥
I'm going back to the Commandant
尽力让他相信这里有个凶手
and try and convince him that there's a murderer abroad.
那我跟 Ben 一起去
Well I'll go with Ben.
不，Jamie，我要你原路返回
No, Jamie, I want you to find your way back//
到变色龙柜台去盯着点 Polly
to the Chameleon kiosk and keep an eye on Polly.
哦！呃，这里是你负责吗？
Oh! Err, are you in charge here?
啊，是的，有什么可以帮你的？
Ah, yes. Can I help you?
有，我叫 Samatha Briggs，我从利物浦来的
Yes. I... I'm Samantha Briggs
and I've come down from Liverpool.
哦，真的啊
Oh, really?
是关于我弟弟的事情，他叫 Brian Brigg
It's about my brother, Brian Briggs -
他怎么了？
What about him?
他来参加你们的一个观光旅游，但他现在不见了
He went on one of your tours,
and now he's disappeared.
对不起，我没明白
I'm sorry, I don't follow.
哎，这真的很简单
Well, it's really very simple.
你们送他去的那个酒店，我试图去找它的电话号码
I tried to get the telephone number
of the hotel you sent him to,
但接线员说没有这样一个地方
and the operator said there was no such place.
哦，接线员肯定搞错了
Well, the operator must have been mistaken then.
于是...我就联系了警方
So... I got in touch with the police
然后他们说 Brian 不在罗马的任何一个酒店里
and they said that Brian
wasn't staying at any hotel in Rome.
哦，也许他改主意了，然后跑去了别的旅游团
Well, um, perhaps he changed his mind
and decided to go on a different tour then.
那你看看这个怎么说？
Well what about this then?
Brian 寄来的明信片，从罗马寄来的！
A post-card from Brian, posted in Rome!
是，这看起来有点奇怪，是不？
Yes, that does seem odd, doesn't it?
呃，我帮你查查你看可以吗？
Erm, would you like me to make some enquiries for you?
那你觉得我大老远从利物浦跑来是为了什么？
Well, what do you think
I've come all the way down from Liverpool for?
既然你都把情况告诉警方了，为什么还自己跑来？
Well - since you've put the matter
with the police, why have you?
警方说每周都有好几打人失踪
Police. They said that dozens of people
go missing every week
而他们没有足够的人全部展开调查
and they haven't got the men to go chasing after them all.
我明白了。你说你弟弟的名字叫什么来着？
I see. What did you say your brother's name was?
Brian Briggs. 你期望我给你拼出来么？
Brian Briggs. Would you like me to spell it for you?
没必要，谢谢你
That won't be necessary, thank you.
我看看我能查出什么来，如果你愿意等的话
I'll see what I can find out, if you don't mind waiting.
Blade 机长在吗不？
Is Captain Blade there?
不在
No.
我必须得跟他通话，很紧急//
Well, I must speak with him - urgently.
关于一个失踪乘客的事情
Enquiries about a missing passenger.
我会让他跟你联系，不会很久的
I'll tell him to contact you. He shouldn't be long.
我要找的那位绅士现在不在
The gentleman I wanted to speak with wasn't available,
他们找他去了。你想要等一会儿吗？
they're trying to find him. Do you want to wait?
我也没有其它事情可做啊，对吧？
Well, I've got nothing else to do, have I?
我就在那边
I'll be over there.
哦，该死！
Oh blast!
有什么事吗？
Is anything the matter?
自以为是的东西！
Stuck up thing!
- 什么？  - 不是说你
- What?  - Not you.
那个女的，她一点也不在乎
That girl! She just couldn't care less.
找你弟弟的事情
About finding your brother.
- 是  - 我不小心听到了
- Yes.   - I couldn't help overhearing.
你觉得他是不是出了什么事？
Do you think something's happened to him.
哦，这个问题，我说不好
Well, that's just it, I don't know.
哦，Brian 倒是能自己照顾自己，不过还是...
Oh, Brian can take care of himself all right, but still...
是，但愿你是对的
Aye, well I hope you're right.
- 你什么意思？  - 我也许可以帮到你
- What d'you mean?  - I might just be able to help you.
但目前我不能告诉任何情况
I can't tell you anything at the moment
但稍后我带你见我一个朋友
but later I'd like you to meet a friend of mine.
我确信他知道怎样处理最好
I'm sure he'll know what's best.
抱歉，先生
Excuse me, sir.
有位绅士要见你
There's a gentleman to see you.
他说了是什么事吗？
Did he say what about?
哦说了，是一具死尸的事
Well yes. It's about a dead body.
带他进来吧
Bring him in.
- 你可以进来吗？  - 谢谢你
- Would you come in, please?  - Thank you.
啊，总指挥，很高兴再次见到你
Ah, Commandant. How nice to see you again.
请接机场警方
Airport Police please.
至少听听我有什么要说的
At least hear what I have to say.
我已经听够你那些废话了
I've heard all I want to from you.
你什么意思，他们都占线？
What do you mean, they're engaged.//
我是总指挥。谢谢你
This is the Commandant. Thank you.
如果你打算跟警方通话，赶紧告诉他们...
If you're going to speak to the police,
then tell them that
机场现在有情况，可能会危及很多人的性命
there's something happening in this airport
that may endanger human lives.
是警方吗？我是总指挥
Hello police? Commandant.
请你们能不能立即派几个人过来
Would you send a couple of men down here at once please.
既然我马上就要被捕了，能不能提个最后的请求？
Since I'm obviously about to be arrested
may I make one last request?
就听我说一分钟
Listen to me for just one minute.
一秒钟也不听
Not for one second.
我已经听够了
I've heard all I want to hear about //
烧焦的纤维、射线枪、消失的尸体。。。
burnt fibres, ray guns, disappearing bodies...
但变色龙观光团的机库的确有过一具死尸！
But there was a dead body in the Chameleon Tours hangar!
你刚才是说“变色龙观光团”？
Did you say "Chameleon Tours"?
- 怎么，你知道它一些情况  - 哦，不知道
- Why, do you know something about it?  - Well, no.
但这位 Crossland 督察想要了解... //
But the Inspector Crossland wanted to know...
好了，Jean，我来处理吧
All right, Jean. I'll handle this.
啊，把这个人带走，锁起来，让他一直待在那儿！
Ah, take this man away,
put him under lock and key and keep him there!
再走近一步，我就把你们炸成碎片！
One step nearer and I'll blow you all to smithereens!
接着！
Catch!
好了，去追！
All right, after him!
都相当清楚了吧，是不？你知道怎么跟她说了？
That's quite clear, is it?
You know what to tell her?
我知道
I do.
一旦你甩掉这个女孩，就把柜台关了
As soon as you've got rid of the girl, close the kiosk
登上下一班飞机
and get on the next flight.
Briggs 小姐
Miss Briggs.
在，你查到什么了吗？
Yes. Have you found anything?
呃，是的，我查到了
Err, well yes, I have.
不过恐怕没有太大的帮助
But I'm afraid it doesn't help very much.
你弟弟的确是搭上了我们去罗马的航班
Your brother definitely did get on our flight to Rome,
但他下飞机之后做了什么，我就没法告诉你了
but what he did when he got off the plane,
I couldn't tell you.
啊，如果你不能，谁能？
Well, if you can't, who can?
Briggs 小姐，我们每周都要跟上千乘客打交道
Miss Briggs, We're dealing with
thousands of passengers every week.
我们不可能跟踪每一个人的行踪
We can't keep track of every single one.
如果我是你，就会回到利物浦去
If I were you, I'd go back to Liverpool.
我确信你弟弟最终会露面的
I'm sure your brother will turn up eventually.
现在，什么别的事情的话，我得关闭柜台了
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have to close this kiosk.
谢谢你什么事都没干
Thanks for nothing.
- 这事还真是有意思  - 为什么？
- There's something funny going on here.   - Why?
我弟弟不见了，而那家伙完全漠不关心
My brother's vanished, and that lot just couldn't care less.
你好，负责这个机场的人叫什么？
Hello? What's the name of the man
who's in charge of this airport?
总指挥？
The Commandant?
好，你能帮我接到他的办公室吗，拜托？
Right, well look, can you put me
through to his office, please?
好了，那接航空控制塔台
All right, then Air Traffic Control
但我想跟我的一个朋友通话//
but I want to speak to a friend of mine
他现在应该跟总指挥在一起
who should be with the Commandant right now...
博士，我期望你见见这位年轻女士
Doctor, I'd like you to meet this young lady.
什么年轻女士？Polly 在哪儿？
What young lady? Where's Polly?
她还在里面
She's still inside.
啊，我一分钟就回来
Ah, I shan't be a minute.
Polly...​
Polly...
但你为什么不听他的？都是真的
But why wouldn't you listen to him? It's all true.
我现在在变色龙机库，而我刚刚发...
I'm in the Chameleon Hangar now and I've just f...
Ben！
Ben!
Ben，你能听到我吗？
Ben, can you hear me?
Ben，你没事吧，能听到我说话吗？Ben！
Ben, are you all right, can you hear me? Ben!
Ben！
Ben!
Ben，你能听到我吗？
Ben, can you hear me?
他是谁？
Who is he?
屏幕上那个博士的一个朋友
A friend of that Doctor on the screen.
他看到那里发生的事情了？
Did he see what happened in there?
他肯定看到了
He must have done.
那他肯定会过来，我们最好给他做点准备
Then he'll be coming here.
We'd better be prepared for him.
首先，处理掉尸体
First, dispose of the body.
他是谁？
Who is he?
他叫 Brian Briggs
His name's Brian Briggs.
据说是一周前来到这里的，度假
Supposed to have come through here
about a week ago, on holiday.
每周都有上千人来到这里
Thousands of people come through here a week.
是，只是试试机会
Aye, well it was just a chance.
- 你还记得那个人吗？  - 是的，我记得他
- Do you remember that man?
- Oh yes, I remember him.
他有通行证，但我想不起他的名字了
He had a pass. But I can't remember his name.
他是我的一个同事，Gascoigne 督察
He's a colleague of mine,
Detective Inspector Gascoigne.
他什么时候回来的？
Now when did he come back?
我没法告诉你，太多面孔了
I couldn't tell you. There are so many faces.
今天早上这里有点状况，他可能那时候溜过去了
There was a bit of bother this morning,
he could have slipped through then.
什么样的状况？
What sort of bother?
有两个没有护照的人//
Two people without passports,
叨叨着说什么在一个机库里面发现了一具尸体
who told some sort of story about a body in a hangar.
- 具体什么情况？  - 啊，只是场闹剧
- What happened?  - Ah, it was all a hoax.
然后这两人跑掉了，机场警察现在还在四处找他们！
These two men they ran away.
The airport police are still looking for them!
你能向我描述一下他们的样子吗？
Can you describe them to me?
其中一个外表有点邋遢，中等个子，穿着一件大衣
One was a scruffy-looking man,
medium-height, wearing a frock-coat,
另一个是个苏格兰小伙子，穿着苏格兰草裙！
the other was a Scots boy dressed in a kilt!
哦，应该不难找到
Oh, shouldn't be too hard to find.
嘿，你觉得我们应该去找你的朋友不？//
Hey, you think we should go after your friend?
他已经走了10分钟了
He's been gone about ten minutes now.
不用，他说了半个小时。现在，我们按他说的做
No, he said half a hour.
Now, we'll do what he said.
嘿，他可真是个怪人，不是吗？
Hey, he is a right weirdy, isn't he?
不是！我期望我能有他的脑子
No! I wish I had his brains.
你倒是挺正常的
You're all right as you are.
变色龙青年观光游通知您，//
Chameleon Youth Tours announce the departure
飞往苏黎世的413航班即将起飞
of their flight Number Four-One-Three to Zurich.
请所有旅客在候机室集合
Will all passengers please
assemble in the departure lounge.
变色龙青年旅游团通知您
Chameleon Youth Tours ann...
嘿，快看，他们现在又打开那个柜台了
Hey, look, they've opened up that kiosk now.
是，不过 Polly 去哪儿了？
Aye, and where's Polly?
请所有旅客在候机室集合
...Will all passengers
please assemble in the departure lounge.
行李箱！
Packing cases!
我能肯定，等你们达到瑞士后的第一件事情
I'm quite sure the first thing you want to do
when you get to Switzerland
就是通知家里的父母
is write home to your parents...
但以免你们没有时间
But in case you don't have time,
变色龙旅游团准备了一些苏黎世的明信片，//
Chameleon Tours have some postcards of Zurich
你们可以现在填写
ready for you to write here.
等你们填写好了，把它交给我/FIXTS
When you've finished your postcards,
give them back to me
我们将会在苏黎世帮你们寄出去
and we'll post them for you in Zurich.
诶，介意吗？
Eh, do you mind?
没事，给
No, go ahead.
你看，苏黎世的明信片
Look! A postcard of Zurich,
贴好了瑞士的邮票，就等着寄了
stamped with a Swiss stamp, all ready to post.
- 怎么了？ - 噢，你真是个好人，对吧
- Well?  - Oh, you're a right one, aren't you.
你没看出来吗？这就能解释为什么我能收到 Brian 的明信片了
Don't you see. This could explain
the card I got from Brian.
它是从罗马寄出的，但并不能说明是他寄的！
It was posted in Rome, but that doesn't
mean to say that he posted it!
哦，我明白了。我们最好把这个情况告诉博士！
Oh I see. We'd better tell the Doctor about this!
呃，他走了多久了？
Er, how long's he been gone?
大概半个小时
Err, about half a hour, now.
- 好，我去找他  - 我跟你一起去
- Right, I'll go and find him.  - I'll come with you.
等一下，孩子，我有句话跟你说
Just a minute, son. I want a word with you.
有谁能帮帮我... 求求你们... 我要窒息了...
Somebody, help me... please... I'm suffocating...
快点，有谁能帮帮我...
Quickly, somebody help me please...
我要窒息了...
I'm suffocating...
帮帮我，求求你们！
Help me, please!